

Varvara Lazarenko

Address Nijmegen, The Netherlands Telephone

+31 6 2662 9839

E-mail varlazoa@gmail.com Date of birth

29.12.1998 (26 years)

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/varvara-lazo

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a recent graduate of the Medical Biology Master program in the specialisation Science, management & Innovation (SMI) at Radboud University. I am inspired by the societal & business aspects of healthcare innovations and fond of using scientific knowledge to create practical, real-world solutions. With a strong biomedical background and a keen interest in disseminating knowledge, I envision a career in consultancy, product management, health technology assessment (HTA), value assessment, or health economics.

EDUCATION

09/2022 - 08/2024

MSc in Medical Biology - Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Specialisation: Science, Management and Innovation
- ✓ GPA 7.63/10.00
- ✓ Principal subjects: Future of health, How Health Systems Work, Sustainable Innovation Management, Methods in Societal Research, Reaching the Sustainable **Development Goals**
- ✓ Projects: «HTA of a Medical Guidance App for International Students in the NL» «A Shared Ownership Model of the Green Corridor, Nijmegen»
 - «A Circular Alternative to Single-Use Cups Within the Dutch Train System»
- ✓ <u>Master thesis</u>: «Potential added value of home telemonitoring technology in elderly) care»

09/2016 - 06/2020

BSc in Biology - Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Specialisation: Human and Animal Physiology
- ✓ GPA 4.83/5.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Human and animal physiology, Electrophysiology of excited cells, Neurochemistry, Physiology of central nervous and visceral systems, Physiology of circulation, Virology, Microbiology
- ✓ <u>Bachelor thesis</u>: «Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats»

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2024 - 08/2024

Intern at Digital Transformation of Rehabilitation Care

HAN University of Applied Sciences - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Added value research of home telemonitoring in elderly care based on the HTA framework presented onto the Quadruple aim
- ✓ Deployment of surveys (22) in Dutch and interviewing (7) medical professionals in English on their home telemonitoring experience/attitude
- ✓ Cost-effectiveness analysis (Markov model cohort simulation) on home telemonitoring in the Netherlands

02/2023 - 08/2023

Intern at Neuronal Networks of Memory

Donders Institute - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ In vivo Ca²⁺ imaging of the retrosplenial cortex in mice during head-fixed virtual social learning
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (mice, handling & feeding)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (Python, DeepLabCut)

08/2021 - 08/2022

Assistant at the Science department of the Contract Research Organization

LABMGMU, LLC - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Developing clinical trial design, synopses, protocols, investigator's brochures for >35 phase I, II, III clinical trials and bioequivalence trials
- √ >30 user interviews (testing the readability of pharmaceuticals' package leaflets)
- ✓ Project management (control of the deadlines; compliance with the sponsor's requirements)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)

10/2020 - 10/2021

Junior Research Assistant at Faculty of Biology

Lomonosov Moscow State University - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Physiological and molecular biology experiments (wire myography, real-time PCR, western blot)
- √ Management of laboratory animals (Wistar rats)
- ✓ Statistical analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)
- ✓ Project management (experiment and research strategy planning)
- ✓ Presentation of the results at two conferences (Oct, 2020; Apr, 2021)

DIGITAL SKILLS

Python (beginner), DeepLabCut, STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism and MS Office softwares

LANGUAGES

Russian (native), English (fluent – C_{1-2}), German (low intermediate – A_2 - B_1), Dutch (beginner – A_2), French (beginner – A_1)

ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS

- 2022-2024 Awarded Orange Tulip Scholarship for the studies at Radboud University
- 2020-2021 Awarded MSU Increased State Academic Scholarship for scientific and academic achievements
 - 2021 Second prize-winner in the Lomonosov Universiade on modern problems of biology

VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITY

- 2024 Mentorship of international exchange and Master's students at the Radboud Intro
- 2023 Organization of the BBB Career Event 2023, Nijmegen
- 2022-2023 Organization of volleyball tournaments in the international volleyball group at Radboud
- 2018-2021 Mentorship of first-year students at Faculty of Biology, MSU, Moscow

HOBBIES

Volleyball, drawing, guitar playing, traveling

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Shvetsova Anastasia A., **Lazarenko Varvara S.**, Gaynullina Dina K., Tarasova Olga S., Schubert Rudolf (2022). TWIK-Related Acid-Sensitive Potassium Channels (TASK-1) Emerge as Contributors to Tone Regulation in Renal Arteries at Alkaline pH. *Frontiers in physiology*, *13*: 895863. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.895863
- **2. Lazarenko Varvara**, Shvetsova Anastasia, Gaynullina Dina, Schubert Rudolph (2020). TASK-1 Channels Play an Anticontractile Role in Rat Septal Coronary Artery Under Pharmacological Blockade of Endothelium. *Artery Research*, *26*(S1): S58. https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048
- 3. Borzykh A.A., Kuzmin I.V., Kiryukhina O.O., Selivanova E.K., Shvetsova A.A., **Lazarenko V.S.**, Los-Arkos Uvarova S., Nesterenko A.M., Tarasova O.S. (2020). Voluntary running training of female rats during gestation: characteristics of an experimental model [in Russian]. *Aviakosmicheskaya i Ekologicheskaya Meditsina*, *54*(2): 89–95. https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639